Habaek.
Habaek.
Nak-bin was going to be used as a sacrificial offering.
Iban a ofrecer a Nak-bin como sacrificio.
It's what foolish humans used to do.
Una tonta costumbre humana antigua.
But Habaek fell in love with the human offering given to us,
Pero Habaek se enamoró de ella.
so shall we say that he was even more foolish than humans?
Se podría decir que fue más tonto que los humanos.
The King of the Land of the Sky had a vain dream of
El rey de la Nación del Cielo tuvo el vanidoso sueño
breaking the rules of the divine realm and building a new order.
de acabar con el reino divino y crear un nuevo orden.
He thought he could achieve it by stealing Habaek's powers.
Para lograr eso, robó los poderes de Habaek.
Habaek.
Habaek.
He promised Habaek's woman eternal life,
Le prometió vida eterna a la mujer de Habaek
and that foolish woman gladly promised him that she'd betray Habaek.
y esa tonta le prometió con gusto que traicionaría a Habaek.
Thus, she fooled Habaek and put him under the curse.
Así que engañó a Habaek y le puso una maldición.
Do you think she ended up gaining eternal life that she so longed for?
¿Crees que obtuvo la vida eterna que tanto anhelaba?
The sun will go down soon.
El sol se esconderá pronto.
Nak-bin.
Nak-bin.
Habaek.
Habaek.
The Queen Mother...
La Reina Madre
wants to kill you.
quiere matarte.
She wants to use your blood...
Usará tu sangre
to break the curse you brought upon us.
para romper tu maldición.
The eternal life you've been desperately longing for
La vida eterna que tanto anhelabas
will be granted to you along with death.
se te concederá junto con la muerte.
Neither nirvana nor reincarnation...
No se te permitirá alcanzar el nirvana
will be allowed.
ni la reencarnación.
Help me.
Ayúdame.
Please.
Por favor.
Save me, Habaek. Please.
Sálvame, Habaek. Por favor.
I will...
Nunca…
never forgive you.
…te perdonaré.
I came to tell you this.
Vine a decirte eso.
Habaek, I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
Habaek, lo siento. Lo siento mucho.
Please, Habaek! I didn't know.
Por favor, Habaek. No lo sabía.
I had no idea that it was a curse.
No sabía que era una maldición.
I did it out of love.
Lo hice por amor.
I wanted to live eternally with you.
Quería vivir para siempre contigo.
I love you, Habaek. I love you...
Te amo, Habaek.
Please. I love you.
Por favor. Te amo.
Habaek!
¡Habaek!
Habaek.
Habaek.
Please don't kill me!
¡Por favor, no me maten!
Please!
¡Por favor!
No! Please!
¡No! ¡Por favor!
No.
¡No!
Habaek! Habaek! Help me!
¡Habaek, ayúdame!
Habaek, please help me.
¡Habaek!
Habaek, please don't kill me!
¡Habaek! ¡No me maten, por favor!
Help...
Ayuda…
However, taking that woman's insignificant life
Sin embargo, tomar su vida no fue suficiente para la Reina Madre.
The Queen Mother wanted her brother and his son to pay for her sins as well.
Exigió que su hermano y su hijo también pagaran por sus pecados.
Please spare our lives.
Le ruego, perdone nuestras vidas.
The brother begged for mercy.
Su hermano rogó por piedad y a cambio de perdonarlos,
and the foolish man promised her
prometió que su familia le serviría a los dioses por siempre.
That's absurd.
Qué absurdo.
And what does that have to do with me?
Eso no es mi culpa.
Even if one of my ancestors betrayed his country,
Aunque hubieran asesinado o robado hace mil años,
what does that have to do with me now?
¿qué tiene que ver conmigo?
Am I supposed to feel guilty for what that woman did?
¿Debo sentirme culpable por lo que hizo esa mujer?
Too bad. You can only feel guilty
Uno solo puede sentirse culpable
when you actually did something wrong.
por las cosas que uno mismo hace.
As for this story, I can't even relate to it.
Esto no me hace sentir culpable.
You really are foolish.
Realmente eres una tonta.
You just don't get it, do you?
No lo entiendes, ¿cierto?
What did Mura say to you?
¿Qué te dijo Mura?
Why do you look so serious?
¿Por qué estás tan serio?
Let's eat.
Comamos.
It's almost dinnertime.
Es casi hora de cenar.
It's pretty amazing that you guys always show up right around dinnertime.
Siempre se aparecen a la hora de la cena.
Gosh, it's gone bad.
Cielos, se echó a perder.
What should we do?
¿Qué hacemos?
Should we have cup noodles?
¿Fideos instantáneos?
What did Mura...
Mura…
say to you?
¿Qué te dijo?
She didn't say much. She just told me your old love story.
No mucho. Me contó una historia de amor antigua.
It wasn't even that interesting.
No era ni interesante.
Sit down.
Siéntate.
-Nak-bin was-- -Yes, Nak-bin.
- Nak-bin era… - Eso, Nak-bin.
That was her name, right?
Así se llamaba, ¿cierto?
I knew it. The story about the woman with the surname Shim was fake.
Sabía que el apellido Shim de tu historia era falso.
The woman, whom you loved so dearly,
La mujer a la que amabas tanto
betrayed you,
te traicionó y fue finalmente castigada.
Then her brother made a stupid pledge. And, apparently, he's my ancestor.
Y su hermano hizo una estúpida promesa.
But the thing is, am I supposed to be responsible
Pero ¿debería ser responsable
for what one of my ancestors did 1,200 years ago?
por algo que hizo mi antepasado hace 1200 años?
Don't you think it's ridiculous?
¿No es ridículo?
I'm utterly baffled.
Estoy muy confundida.
What is it that you really want to say?
¿Qué quieres decir realmente?
Go back.
Regresa.
Return to where you belong.
Regresa a donde perteneces.
Please go back.
Por favor.
And please move out as soon as possible.
Y múdate cuanto antes, por favor.
I decide when I will leave.
Yo decido cuándo me voy.
I heard you did nothing.
Oí que no hiciste nada.
Do whatever it takes to persuade him.
Haz lo que sea para persuadirlo.
When the woman you loved...
Cuando la mujer que amabas
was dying,
estaba muriendo,
you did nothing.
no hiciste nada.
You really are foolish.
No tienes remedio.
You just don't get it, do you?
No lo entiendes, ¿cierto?
I'm not telling you to feel guilty.
No quiero que te sientas culpable.
I'm asking you to let Habaek go.
Quiero que lo dejes ir.
Let him go.
Déjalo ir.
I know you can figure out that is what you should do.
Sabes que es lo correcto.
It makes me so angry to admit this,
Me enfurece admitirlo,
but I have to.
pero debo hacerlo.
That fool...
Ese tonto…
is in love with you.
…se enamoró de ti.
Do you understand?
¿Entiendes?
He'll go back anyway.
Va a regresar.
But he's torn.
Está dividido.
He can't only think about himself.
No puede pensar solo en él.
Habaek represents the Land of Water,
Habaek representa a la Nación del Agua. Lo es todo para él.
Like you said, he has to go back eventually.
Como dijiste, debe regresar.
Do you know what the biggest irony is?
¿Sabes cuál es la mayor ironía?
If he doesn't ascend the throne,
Si no asciende al trono,
he'll be nothing.
no será nada.
That means Habaek will choose to go back, no matter how torn he is now.
Habaek elegirá regresar sin importar cuán dividido esté.
Then everything is fine.
Entonces estará bien.
Let him go before he destroys himself...
Déjalo ir antes de que se destruya,
while he still has the strength to get over it.
mientras aún pueda superarlo.
Let him go, please.
Déjalo ir, por favor.
After losing Nak-bin,
Después de perder a Nak-bin,
he punished himself and became a wreck.
se echó la culpa y quedó destrozado.
I don't want to see that again.
No quiero ver eso de nuevo.
I beg you.
Te lo ruego.
Please don't hold him back,
Por favor, no lo retengas
like Nak-bin did.
como lo hizo Nak-bin.
I wish I could cry.
Ojalá pudiera llorar.
Like you said,
Como dijiste,
I wish I could get drunk.
ojalá pudiera embriagarme.
I wish I could do...
Ojalá pudiera hacer las estupideces que hacen los humanos.
I'm so angry.
Estoy tan enojada
This anger is driving me nuts.
que me estoy volviendo loca.
I admitted in front of her
Le admití
that he's in love with her.
que la ama.
You didn't have to.
No era necesario.
Why did that have to be...
¿Por qué tenía que ser la única forma
the only way I could send him back?
de hacer que regresara?
Then you did what you had to do.
Hiciste lo que debías.
You don't need to be angry...
No deberías enojarte
or regret anything.
ni arrepentirte de nada.
I'll give you a hug.
Te daré un abrazo.
If you'd let me,
Si me dejaras,
I could beat Habaek to a pulp.
podría darle una paliza a Habaek.
Don't you dare.
No te atrevas.
See? I knew you'd say that.
¿Ves? Sabía que dirías eso.
Namsuri.
Namsuri.
Wake up, Namsuri.
Despierta, Namsuri.
-Where were you yesterday? -Here and there.
- ¿A dónde fuiste ayer? - Por ahí.
Were your feelings hurt because I worked to get a gift for the servant?
¿Te ofendió que trabajara para comprarle un regalo?
Pardon? Oh, well...
¿Qué?
Yes, it really hurt my feelings.
Sí, me ofendió.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
You drive the duck boat during the day in the scorching heat
Trabajas bajo el calor del día
and work as a delivery guy at night while battling mosquitoes.
y luego de noche, aguantando los mosquitos.
I know you're doing all of that to serve me well.
Sé que lo haces para servirme bien.
Even though I'm strong and healthy, all I do is take warm baths
Aunque soy fuerte y saludable, solo tomo baños tibios
and enjoy the food, books, and fruit juice you get me.
y disfruto de la comida y cosas que me traes.
All I do is eat and drink.
Lo único que hago es comer.
I'm well aware of it.
Lo sé muy bien.
No! Please forgive me for my grave sins, My Lord!
¡No, por favor! ¡Perdone mis graves pecados, señor!
You weren't actually expecting me to say such things, were you?
¿Esperabas que dijera eso?
No, My Lord.
No, mi señor.
Then go tell the servant...
Entonces ve y dile a la sirviente
that we should have breakfast.
que desayunemos.
Pardon? Sure, right away.
¿Qué?
That was a good meal.
Estuvo rico.
Give me your phone.
Tu teléfono.
Take care of them for us.
Cuida de ellos.
I heard that the service needs to be canceled.
Cancela el servicio.
The newspaper too.
El periódico también.
Please also get rid of my clothes and books.
Y deshazte de mi ropa y mis libros.
What do you mean, My Lord?
¿De qué está hablando?
Also, call Namsuri's boss at the duck boat tour company for him.
Y habla con el jefe de Namsuri.
Don't stay out late.
No salgas tarde.
I heard there's a type of light
Oí que venden luces que se encienden solas de noche.
Get it for your door.
Ponla en tu puerta.
And don't eat cup noodles all the time.
Y no comas tantos fideos instantáneos.
Make yourself proper meals, even if you're not a good cook.
Debes alimentarte bien.
Also, don't clean the house once every million years.
Y no dejes pasar tanto tiempo para limpiar la casa.
Try to clean often.
Hazlo más seguido.
It'll be easier that way.
Así es más fácil.
For the streetlight in the alley,
Y sobre la luz de la calle,
I heard you can submit a complaint when it's not working.
escuché que puedes presentar una queja.
Even if it feels a hassle, it's better than walking in the dark.
No deberías caminar en la oscuridad.
Just submit a complaint.
Presenta una queja.
You enjoy doing things like that anyway.
Disfrutas hacer esas cosas.
Well...
Bueno…
-Namsuri. -Yes?
- Namsuri. - ¿Sí?
Give us some privacy.
Déjanos solos.
Sure.
Claro.
I told you that it shows on your face when you lie. Do you remember?
¿Recuerdas que puedo notar cuando mientes?
But this time, I couldn't tell.
Esta vez no pude hacerlo.
I've realized that you truly want me to leave.
Me di cuenta de que realmente quieres que me vaya.
I told you that I'm your god...
Te dije que era tu dios
and bluffed that I'd protect you.
y prometí que te protegería.
It embarrasses me.
Estoy avergonzado.
Why did I make a promise that I cannot keep?
¿Por qué prometí algo que no puedo cumplir?
I regret it.
Me arrepiento.
I want to ask you if I can leave...
Si me voy,
and if you'll be okay.
¿estarás bien?
I want to ask you how you really feel,
Quiero saberlo.
but you'll probably be okay because I've done nothing for you.
Pero seguro estarás bien, porque no he hecho nada por ti.
I'll be fine.
Estaré bien.
Like you said yourself, you've done nothing for me.
Como dijiste, no has hecho nada por mí.
Your absence won't even be noticeable.
Apenas notaré tu ausencia.
I'll be a bit lonely, but I'll be fine.
Me sentiré sola, pero estaré bien.
I've told you. I'm good at enduring things because I'm lesser.
Soy buena soportando cosas porque soy una luchadora.
All right, then.
Muy bien.
-Are you going to leave today? -I'm leaving now.
- ¿Cuándo te vas? - Ahora.
Then I'll give you a ride to Gangwon Province.
Entonces te llevaré a Gangwon.
No, it's okay.
No te molestes.
Let's just part ways here.
Aquí nos separamos.
Let's go, Namsuri.
Vamos, Namsuri.
Yes, My Lord.
Sí, mi señor.
Take care, Ms. Descendant.
Cuídese, Srta. Descendiente.
Lord Judong told me to wait for him, though.
El Sr. Judong me dijo que lo esperara.
Goodbye.
Adiós.
Farewell.
Hasta siempre.
You need a stand-in for a reporter?
¿Reemplazar a un reportero?
What's it about?
¿De qué se trata?
The sailfin...
¿Pescar voladores japoneses?
The thing is, I'm prone to severe seasickness.
Es que me mareo en el mar.
I can't really be on a small fishing boat. That's right.
No puedo subirme a barcos de pesca pequeños.
You don't want to do it?
- ¿No quieres hacerlo? - No, no es eso.
Gosh, I'm so disappointed.
Qué decepción.
Okay, I'll do it.
Bien, lo haré.
But you have to make sure I look very pretty in it.
Pero asegúrate de que me vea muy linda.
All right. Then I'll see you tomorrow. Bye.
Está bien. Nos vemos mañana. Adiós.
-What? -Tell him you don't want to do it.
- ¿Qué? - Dile que no quieres ir.
What do you know?
¿Qué sabes tú?
If I'm that choosy, I'll never be able to make a name for myself.
Si soy tan exigente, nunca podré ser famosa.
-Give me your phone. -Hey, what are you doing now?
- Dame eso. - ¿Qué estás haciendo?
-Hey, Ja-ya. -Hello.
- Hola, Ja-ya. - Hola.
I'm Ja-ya's manager. You can call me Mr. Min.
Soy el Sr. Min, su representante.
-All right. What can I do for you? -Mr. Gwon.
- ¿Qué se le ofrece? - Sr. Gwon.
If Ja-ya gets on the boat,
Si Ja-ya se sube al barco,
you'll need to clean it right away. Will you be okay with that?
después tendrá que limpiarlo.
-I have to clean it? -That's right.
- ¿Limpiarlo? - Así es.
She'll throw up.
Porque va a vomitar.
She'll vomit nonstop.
Una y otra vez.
Forget catching fish.
Olvide la pesca porque no podrá trabajar.
Let's cancel it, then.
- Cancelemos entonces. - Está bien.
Sorry for the inconvenience.
Disculpe las molestias. Avísenos si hay otros trabajos.
Thanks.
Gracias.
-It's been canceled. -What?
- Lo cancelaron. - ¿Qué?
Okay, thanks.
Bueno, gracias.
I have to deliver some juice, so I should get going.
Tengo que hacer algunas entregas. Debo irme.
Stay still.
Quédate quieto.
I told you to stay still!
¡Que te quedes quieto!
What's wrong? Is it acting up?
¿Se está portando mal?
Shall I get you a new one? A mannequin, perhaps?
Quizá deba conseguirte un maniquí.
How about something that looks like Brad Pitt?
Uno parecido a Brad Pitt.
Does such a thing actually exist?
¿Existe algo así?
Yes, of course.
Por supuesto.
I know you like handsome guys.
Sé que te gustan guapos.
Maybe that one isn't working because it's simply not your type.
Quizá ese no está funcionando porque no es tu tipo.
Then should we try that? Although I don't love the idea.
Intentemos eso, aunque no me gusta la idea.
Why are you laughing?
¿Por qué te ríes?
Well, do you really believe...
¿Realmente crees
that will solve the problem?
que eso resolverá el problema?
The problem is you, you bonehead.
El problema eres tú, boba.
There's nothing wrong with the actors.
Los actores no son el problema.
The problem is you.
Lo eres tú.
You scare them when you should be making them fall in love with you.
En vez de enamorarlos, los asustas.
I will freeze your tongue and--
Te congelaré la lengua y…
All right. Let's say your co-star did this.
Digamos que tu compañero hace esto.
"Don't you dare kiss me.
"No te atrevas a besarme
If you do, I'll freeze your tongue and crush it."
o te congelaré la lengua".
If that was the message he got, would he want to kiss you?
Si escucha eso, ¿tendría ganas de besarte?
Good. That's how you do it. Okay?
Así es como se hace, ¿bien?
Close your mouth. You're not shooting an adult movie.
Cierra la boca. No es una película para adultos.
I've been cutting you too much slack these days.
Soy demasiado clemente contigo.
Let me know whenever you need someone to practice with.
Avísame si quieres practicar.
I'd be better than a mannequin.
Sería mejor que un maniquí.
Yes.
Sí.
Fine.
Está bien.
I'll do it. I said, I'll do it!
¡Dije que lo haré!
Has the kissing scene been scheduled?
¿Reagendaron la escena del beso?
The penalty won't do, right?
El castigo no sirvió, ¿cierto?
Humans are like that.
Los humanos son así.
When their pride is hurt, even money can't do anything.
Cuando hieren su orgullo, ni siquiera el dinero puede resolverlo.
I mean, look at So-a.
Es como con So-a.
She returned the car as soon as Habaek left.
Devolvió el auto apenas Habaek se fue.
How's she holding up?
¿Cómo está?
My gosh! Stop right there.
¡Dios mío! Detente ahí.
He's such a happy, energetic kid.
Pero qué niño más feliz y enérgico.
Oh, you dropped it. Good job. You're so adorable.
Se te cayó, buen trabajo. Eres tan adorable.
All right, let's go over there.
Bien, vamos para acá.
What an innocent little munchkin.
Qué niño más bueno.
I'm really sorry.
Lo siento mucho.
No problem. He has such a pure soul.
No se preocupe. Tiene un corazón tan puro.
-Take care. -Bye.
- Cuídese. - Adiós.
Bye. See you.
Adiós. Nos vemos.
Get home safely.
Que lleguen bien.
My goodness.
Dios mío.
-He's so cute. -Why are you so chipper?
- Qué lindo. - ¿Por qué estás tan alegre?
I'm totally frazzled.
Yo estoy exhausto.
Isn't he cute?
¿No era lindo?
You're so negative about everything.
Qué negativo eres.
That little boy is full of energy.
El niño estaba lleno de energía.
I got a call from the bank to say we're eligible for the loan.
El banco dijo que te aprobaron el préstamo,
It's all thanks to Mr. Ma's father.
gracias al padre del señor Ma.
Really? That's such great news.
¿En serio? Qué buenas noticias.
Contact Mr. Bang as soon as we receive the money.
Avísale al señor Bang.
Did you tell him we'll pay more deposit?
- ¿Le contaste sobre el depósito? - Sí.
Great, perfect. So many good things are happening. We even have more patients.
Perfecto.
We just have one new patient.
Es solo uno nuevo.
Why are you so hyper these days?
Estás muy hiperactiva.
Why are you so negative about everything?
¿Por qué eres tan negativo con todo?
Isn't that mine?
¿Eso no es mío?
Yes. I saw that you have a lot of this,
Sí, vi que tienes muchos, así que saqué unos cuantos.
I want to start taking some supplements for my health.
Quiero empezar a tomar suplementos.
I should put my health before anything else.
Debo preocuparme de mi salud
I have to stay healthy if I want to go to Vanuatu.
si quiero ir a Vanuatu.
Then buy some for yourself. Why steal mine?
Pero ¿por qué robas mis cosas?
What? I stole yours?
¿Qué? ¿Robar?
Hey, why are you so obsessed with these?
¿Por qué estás tan obsesionado con esto?
It's because Mr. Ma got them for me.
Porque el señor Ma me los dio a mí.
Get out.
Vete.
Dr. Yun.
Dra. Yun.
So-a, did you ask Ji-won to set you up with someone?
¿Tienes una cita a ciegas?
-Yes. -What?
- Sí. - ¿Qué?
Why is she telling everyone?
¿Por qué Ji-won les dijo a todos?
Oh, right. I told her to tell everyone. I'm so forgetful. Oh, dear.
Cierto, yo le dije que lo hiciera. Qué despistada.
My goodness!
Dios mío.
I'm sorry, guys.
Lo siento.
Why are you so shocked that I'm going on a blind date?
¿Por qué te sorprende tanto?
Hey, I'm totally fine.
Oye, estoy bien.
I knew it. It's really no big deal.
En verdad no es para tanto.
I thought I'd be devastated, but not at all.
Pensé que estaría devastada, pero no fue así.
Had I known it'd be this easy, I would've had more fun with him.
De haber sabido que sería tan fácil, me habría divertido más con él.
Too bad.
Qué lástima.
You don't get it?
¿No lo entiendes?
Do you know why there usually isn't much romance in crime dramas?
Las series de crimen no tienen romance
It's because they're too busy.
porque tienen demasiados problemas.
They're so busy solving problems that they don't have time for romance.
No les queda tiempo para el romance.
Do you see what I'm getting at?
¿Entiendes?
If I were to categorize my life under one genre, it wouldn't be romance.
Si mi vida fuera una telenovela, no sería romántica.
-What I'm trying to say is-- -I heard you!
- Lo que intento decir… - ¡Ya te oí!
I get it.
Te entiendo.
You're embarrassing me.
Me estás avergonzando.
I'm so happy that you two broke up.
Me alegra que hayan terminado.
But I can't really say this is better than you crying your eyes out.
Pero no sé si esto es mejor a que estuvieras llorando.
Why? I'm a psychiatrist too.
Y lo digo porque también soy psiquiatra.
Also, romance is considered a genre as well, okay?
- Además, el género romántico sí existe. - Estás loca.
You always bragged about having a knack for enduring pain.
Siempre te jactaste de poder soportar el dolor.
I have to get back to work. I'm expecting a patient.
Debo irme. Tengo un paquete.
I have to say, I'm disappointed in Namsuri as well.
Me apena que Namsuri también se vaya.
I should've just made a move.
Debí tomar la iniciativa.
She said it wouldn't take long, so she'll be back shortly.
Dijo que que regresaría pronto.
Okay.
Bien.
Well...
Bueno…
You don't need to worry about me.
No se preocupe por mí.
When Dr. Yun finds a good partner,
Cuando la Dra. Yun encuentre un compañero,
I'll be on my way. I should get married too, you know.
yo seguiré mi camino y también me casaré.
All right.
Bien.
The irony is that she has many emotional wounds because of us.
La ironía es que tiene muchos traumas por nuestra culpa.
Her father was always too busy taking care of us.
Su padre siempre estaba ocupado cuidando de nosotros.
It is true that he was more attentive to us,
Nos prestaba más atención a nosotros
and she was bullied in school on top of that.
y además la acosaban en la escuela.
I even saw kids telling her to get lost,
Hasta los niños la molestaban y decían que olía como un mendigo.
She hasn't told you any of this yet?
¿No le había contado esto?
I'm sorry. I thought she had already told you everything.
Lo siento. Pensé que ya lo sabía.
Be nicer to her, please.
Sea más amable con ella.
You should dissuade her from going on that blind date.
Dígale que no vaya a esa cita a ciegas.
Dr. Yun is going on a blind date?
¿La Dra. Yu tiene una cita a ciegas?
Oh, you're already here.
Ya llegó.
It's too late for me to apologize
Es demasiado tarde para disculparme por lo que pasó, ¿no?
It's okay. I should apologize too.
Está bien. También debería disculparme.
I scared you, didn't I?
¿La asusté?
Did you have a bad dream or something?
¿Tuvo una pesadilla o algo así?
-Yes. -Is it related to your sleep disorder?
Sí.
As I've said before, you should try to think about something else.
Como dije antes, debería pensar en otras cosas.
But I know it's not easy.
Pero sé que no es fácil.
Then why don't we try this?
Intentemos algo.
You said you experienced something that reminded you of your past.
Dijo que experimentó algo que le recordó su pasado.
Could you tell me about it?
¿Podría contarme sobre eso?
Will this be too hard as well?
¿Es demasiado difícil?
I met people whose paths I never wanted to cross.
Conocí a gente que nunca quise conocer.
Who are they?
¿Quiénes son?
They want to lock me up in my past.
Quieren encerrarme en mi pasado.
-Could you please elaborate? -They criticize me.
- ¿Podría darme más detalles? - Me critican.
They remind me of...
Me hacen recordar
my past.
mi pasado.
Your unhappy past... is not something to be criticized.
Su pasado infeliz
No one can decide exactly how their life will unfold.
Nadie puede decidir cómo será su vida.
Is there something else?
¿Hay algo más?
Do you not want to talk about it today?
¿No quiere hablar de eso aún?
Then there's nothing we can do today.
Entonces no hay nada que podamos hacer hoy.
-I'm sorry. -It's okay.
- Lo siento. - No se preocupe.
It looks like you need more time.
Solo necesita tiempo.
But you know what?
Pero ¿sabe qué?
You need to trust me more.
Debería confiar más en mí.
Let's have dinner together.
Cenemos juntos.
Sorry?
¿Perdón?
I don't spend time with my patients outside of the clinic--
No suelo salir con mis pacientes…
Don't read too much into it. Just have dinner with me.
No me malentienda.
We never get hungry. Why do you want to eat at mealtimes like humans do?
¿Por qué te gusta salir a cenar si no nos da hambre?
"Life itself is the proper binge,"
"La vida misma es un atracón",
said a human called Julia something.
dijo una humana llamada Julia algo.
But we're not human.
Pero no somos humanos.
You said you wanted to do all the lame things that humans do.
Dijiste que querías hacer lo que hacen los humanos.
I'm still angry. Do you know that?
Sigo molesto, ¿lo sabía?
-Sorry? -There are still hard feelings.
- ¿Perdón? - Estoy resentido.
I just wanted to have dinner with you. Why did you push me away?
Solo quería cenar con usted. ¿Por qué no quería?
Well, I was just...
Bueno, estaba…
How do you form a friendship, Dr. Yun?
¿Cómo se forma una amistad, Dra. Yun?
-Pardon? -You know what?
- ¿Cómo? - ¿Sabe qué?
I know all about your financial situation,
Sé de su situación financiera y cómo hacerla enojar.
I know how thoughtful you are,
Sé que es considerada, aunque actúe como si no lo fuera.
You'd rather bear losses yourself.
Sé que aguantar las cosas sola es su especialidad.
I also know who you like
Sé quién le gusta y por qué tiene el corazón roto.
I learned about your childhood too.
También supe de su infancia.
I know your address and resident registration number.
Hasta conozco sus datos personales.
Oh, sorry. I have a photographic memory.
Lo siento. Tengo memoria fotográfica.
It's not like I stalked you to obtain all this information.
No es que la acechara para saber todo esto.
You told me everything yourself.
Usted misma me lo contó.
You also know a lot about me.
Usted también sabe mucho de mí.
You've consoled and encouraged me.
Me ha consolado y alentado.
Now, how can friendship grow from here?
¿Cómo puede crecer una amistad desde aquí?
Are you saying we should become friends?
¿Deberíamos ser amigos?
Don't you think we can be friends now?
¿No cree que ya lo somos?
I'm rich. I also have a healthy mindset.
Soy rico y sensato.
I'm commonsensical, polite, hardworking, and handsome.
Soy trabajador, apuesto y cultivo árboles.
I even grow trees. I think I'm pretty awesome.
Soy bastante genial.
This is starting to hurt my pride.
Esto hiere mi orgullo.
It's not like I'm asking you to marry me. All I want is friendship.
No le estoy pidiendo matrimonio. Solo ser su amigo.
Do I really have to list all of these things?
¿Tengo que enumerar todas estas cosas?
Don't make a scene. Let's just leave.
No armes un escándalo.
There's a restaurant I know. Let's go there.
Conozco otro restaurante.
Jingeon, take her home.
Jingeon, llévala a casa.
Do you really not know why he's being like that?
¿Sabes por qué se pone así?
That can't be.
No puede ser.
You know, don't you?
Lo sabes, ¿cierto?
Why is it that you never talk?
¿Por qué nunca hablas?
Let's go. Come on.
Bien, vámonos.
Do you know that I'm still a little mad at you?
¿Sabía que aún estoy un poco molesto con usted?
What?
¿Qué?
The hard feelings are still there.
Aún estoy resentido.
I'm quite picky too.
Soy bastante exigente.
It's not like I ask everyone to be my friend.
No es que le pida a todos que sean mis amigos.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
You really hold a grudge, don't you?
De verdad guarda rencor, ¿no?
Then I have to say something too.
Yo también tengo quejas. Quiere ser mi amigo, pero no confía en mí.
I'm your psychiatrist and friend, but your sessions are going nowhere.
Soy su psiquiatra y amiga, pero las sesiones no avanzan.
How do you explain it?
¿Cómo lo explica?
Is it because you can't trust me as a psychiatrist?
¿No confía en mí como psiquiatra?
-No, that's not why. -Okay.
- No es por eso. - Bien.
I can't force you to trust me. I'll make more effort instead.
No puedo obligarlo a confiar en mí, pero me esforzaré.
And this plush toy is so cute.
Qué peluche tan lindo.
I have to go.
Debo irme.
Can I take that?
¿Me da ese peluche?
Isn't it cute? My friend and I designed it together.
¿No es lindo? Lo diseñamos con mi amigo.
It came with cups as a set, but all the cups have been sold.
Venía con unas tazas, pero las vendimos todas.
-How much-- -I'll pay.
- ¿Cuánto cuesta? - Yo pago.
What are you doing? I'm getting you a gift to celebrate our friendship.
¿Qué hace? Es un regalo por nuestra amistad.
I'm too old to get a plush toy as a gift.
Soy demasiado vieja para que me regalen un peluche.
-How much is it? -It's 45,000 won.
- ¿Cuánto cuesta? - Son 45 000 wones.
Hello?
¿Aló?
Okay. I'll leave right away.
De acuerdo. Voy enseguida.
It looks like I should get going. Something came up at the hotel.
Surgió algo en el hotel, así que debo irme.
I had a great time today.
Lo pasé bien hoy.
I'm sorry I can't drive you home.
Lamento no poder llevarla.
Get home safely. I'll see you soon.
Que llegue bien. Nos vemos.
HABAEK YUN SO-A
HABAEK, YUN SO-A
What is this place?
¿Dónde estoy?
-Don't you remember? -Remember what?
- ¿No lo recuerdas? - ¿Recordar qué?
Why are you reading it silently? You're mean.
¿Por qué lo lees en silencio?
You can't even read the first sentence aloud for me?
¿No me puedes leer la primera oración?
I'll tell you to stop reading if I don't like what I hear.
Te avisaré si no me gusta lo que escucho.
I know it's embarrassing to read something out loud.
Sé que es vergonzoso leer en voz alta.
"How did we meet?
"¿Cómo nos conocimos?
One day, a butterfly flew like a petal
Un día, una mariposa voló como un pétalo
and made a small flutter."
e hizo un leve aleteo".
Once, I read the page of the book you used to read aloud to myself.
"Una día, leí la página del libro que solías leerme en voz alta.
Once, I sat on the chair you used to sit on
Una día, me senté en la silla que usabas
and closed my eyes
y cerré los ojos
in order to feel your warmth.
para poder sentir tu calor.
Once, I even caressed the rim of the cup you used to use
Una día, acaricié el borde de la taza que solías usar
with my fingertips.
con las yemas de los dedos".
"How did we...
"¿Cómo es que nos conocimos y terminamos aquí?
Were we able to reach love
¿Alcanzamos el amor
because we walked through such lovely moments together?
porque tuvimos esos momentos tan lindos juntos?".
-An inevitable miracle." -"An inevitable miracle.
"Un milagro inevitable.
I suppose I didn't want to think...
Supongo que no quería pensar
that we met by a mere coincidence.
que nos conocimos por una mera coincidencia.
So,
Así que lo único que puedo hacer
You can stop reading. Let's go eat now.
Vayamos a comer.
I'll read the rest myself.
Leeré el resto sola.
"...to love you.
"…para amarte.
At the moment,
Por el momento,
I am passing through your love."
estoy pasando por tu amor".
Why can't you do it for me?
¿Por qué no me ayuda?
I want to keep coming here,
Quiero seguir viniendo aquí,
so you can just prepare the medication yourself.
así que deme la receta médica.
Why did he have to complain about such a thing?
¿Por qué se quejó de algo así?
Mr. Shin called earlier
El señor Shin llamó
and suggested sending the employees here directly from now on.
y sugirió enviar a los empleados directamente.
-That would be nice. -See?
- Eso sería bueno. - ¿Ves?
He's the only one who understands you.
Es el único que te entiende.
How does the afternoon look?
¿Cómo luce la tarde?
You have one appointment with Mr. Ma.
Tienes una cita con el Sr. Ma.
You said you were okay.
Dijiste que estabas bien.
But you don't seem okay at all.
Pero no luces para nada bien.
You kept talking about the winners, lessers, and losers.
Hablabas de los ganadores y los luchadores.
You kept bringing up that pretentious nonsense,
Presumías de eso, pero mírate ahora.
You seem as though you drank way more than you can handle.
Pareciera que bebiste mucho
It looks like you're still struggling to sober up.
y estás luchando con la resaca.
That's obviously not the case
No es el caso,
-because I'm the one who dumped you. -You did.
- porque yo te dejé. - Lo hiciste.
But it doesn't feel like it, does it?
Pero no sientes eso, ¿no?
You're probably hating me for not being able to spot your lies.
Seguro me estás odiando por no poder notar tus mentiras.
Do you realize it now?
¿Lo entiendes ahora?
It's impossible to not hurt anyone.
Es imposible no lastimar a nadie.
Just like how the one who's loved by everyone is the worst person.
Así como tampoco puedes ser amado por todos.
I mean, think about that mysterious number you went on about.
Es como el número misterioso del que hablabas.
live certain moments as if that day is going to be their last day.
en los que viven como si fuera su último día,
They instinctively know that they must live today in order to see tomorrow.
porque saben que deben vivir el presente para ver el mañana.
They don't live in fear that tomorrow may not be the same as today.
No viven con el miedo de que el futuro no sea igual que ayer.
I'm talking about those who believe they can live
Hablo de los que pueden vivir
the rest of their lives with the memories they've collected today.
el resto de sus vidas con los recuerdos que van juntando.
Isn't that much wiser than looking for an imaginary number
¿No es eso más sabio que inventar una solución imposible
to prevent everyone from getting hurt?
para evitar el sufrimiento?
You said the square of an imaginary number ends up being less than zero.
Dijiste que debías buscar otro valor para X.
You're not even human.
Ni siquiera eres humano.
How come you never have an umbrella? You'll go bald.
¿Por qué nunca llevas paraguas?
What?
¿Qué?
I guess she's still in love with that water demon.
Supongo que sigue enamorada de ese demonio del agua.
Goodness.
Dios mío.
-What's up? -Come see me if you have some time.
- ¿Aló? - Ven a verme si tienes tiempo.
Yes.
Sí.
Habaek left.
Habaek se fue.
Did our servant tell you?
¿Nuestra sirvienta te contó?
What a funny woman.
Qué mujer tan graciosa.
What did she want in exchange?
¿Qué te pidió a cambio? ¿Que la consolaras?
I wouldn't be asking you...
No te preguntaría si la Srta. Yun me hubiera contado.
Fine. I came because I also have something to say.
Bien.
Please take care of her. No, actually...
Cuídala.
Yes.
Sí.
Just make her yours. You can have her.
Puedes quedarte con ella.
A divine servant, my foot.
¿Sirvienta divina? Sí, claro.
We don't need her. We don't even care, but...
Ni siquiera la necesitamos, pero…
This is just so annoying.
Qué molesto.
I'm not obsessed with being seen as the nice one.
No me gusta ser la buena.
-Are you trying to be responsible? -No, it's not that.
- ¿Intentas ser responsable? - No es eso.
You may not believe me,
Puede que no me creas,
but I don't think humans deserve to become miserable because of gods.
pero no creo que los humanos deban sufrir por los dioses.
-So-- -Then shouldn't you tell me...
- Así que… - Entonces, ¿no deberías decirme
to make her happy...
que la haga feliz
rather than tell me to just have her?
en lugar de que me quede con ella?
I don't care what you do. Just help her forget Habaek.
No me importa lo que hagas mientras olvide a Habaek.
That's not something I can easily do.
Eso no será fácil.
Give it a try.
Inténtalo.
You were planning on doing that anyway.
Igual planeabas hacerlo.
And I want you to marry her. Stay by her side until the day she dies.
Y cásate con ella. Quédate a su lado hasta que muera.
Make sure no other man can even think about being with her.
Asegúrate de que ningún otro hombre piense en estar con ella.
That's the only way we can completely cut off ties with her.
Esa es la única forma de cortar lazos con ella.
This must end for her own sake.
Esto debe terminar por su propio bien.
I want you...
Quiero que la ayudes.
What is it now?
¿Qué pasa ahora?
You scared me. Why do you always show up so quietly...
Me asustaste.
and startle me?
y me asustas así?
-Well, how much do you get paid monthly? -Why do you ask?
¿Cuánto te pagan?
Really? I don't need that money.
¿En serio?
All right, okay. Sit down.
Está bien. Siéntate.
Then just keep being a good friend like you've always been.
Entonces sigue siendo un buen amigo como siempre lo has sido.
Do you really want counseling from me?
¿De verdad quieres que te aconseje?
Are you being serious?
¿Hablas en serio?
You said you'll do it if I pay you.
Dijiste que lo harías si te pagaba.
If you're serious, there's something you need to do first.
- Si hablas en serio, necesitaré algo. - ¿Qué cosa?
-Use honorifics when you call me. -What?
- Trátame de usted. - ¿Qué?
My gosh.
Dios mío.
What kind of nonsense is that?
¿Qué tonterías dices?
You don't want to do it?
¿No quieres?
Forget it, then.
Pues olvídalo.
Wait. Hey, how old are you?
Espera, ¿cuántos años tienes?
From what I understand, we're the same age.
Según sé, tenemos la misma edad.
Then I can't use honorifics. I was born in January.
Entonces no puedo hacerlo, porque nací en enero.
I was born on January 1, at 12:01 a.m.
Yo nací el 1 de enero a las 12:01 a. m.
-But why? -What do you mean?
- ¿Qué? - ¿No es suficiente?
You don't want counseling?
¿No quieres mis consejos? Entonces, olvídalo.
Sir!
¡Señor!
Fine, I'll talk to you politely from now on.
Bien, lo trataré de usted.
Good. What is it that you want to talk to me about?
Bien.
You didn't give me proper advice on what happened last time.
No me dio el consejo adecuado sobre lo que pasó el otro día.
Why do you think Mr. Shin hugged me from behind?
¿Por qué me abrazó el Sr. Shin?
I wasn't mistaken.
No estaba equivocada.
He keeps acting like a bad guy.
Sigue siendo pesado conmigo.
Now that we've decided to do this properly,
Como decidimos hacer esto,
I'll be responsible and give you proper advice.
seré responsable y te daré el consejo adecuado.
From what I understand, he's in love with your friend, Ms. Yun So-a.
Según sé, está enamorado de tu amiga, la señorita Yun So-a.
So just drink some ice-cold water and come to your senses.
Así que acéptalo y entra en razón.
-What? -Now, it's crystal clear, right?
- ¿Qué? - Ahora lo tienes claro.
This is why all the girls at church always ask me for advice.
Por eso las chicas de la iglesia me piden consejo.
Grandpa, kick her out of your building. Kick her out right now!
Abuelo, échala de tu edificio. ¡Échala ahora mismo!
You can't kick her out?
¿Puedes echarla?
If you don't, I'll move back to the US. I'll go live with Mom!
Si no lo haces, me iré a vivir a EE. UU. con mamá.
I'm going to leave you!
¡Te dejaré solo!
Why did you ask me to come by? I'm busy.
¿Para qué me llamaste? Estoy ocupada.
Go back outside and come in again.
Vuelve a entrar.
What?
¿Qué?
Why?
¿Por qué?
My gosh, I don't even know. I should've just gone for it back then.
Cielos, no lo sé. Debí haber actuado antes.
What are you saying? Why did you want to see me?
¿Por qué querías verme?
Have we done a birth chart reading?
¿He leído tu carta astral?
-Tell me your date and time of birth. -Gosh, don't bother.
- ¿Cuándo naciste? - No es necesario.
Just tell me. It's because you keep appearing in my dreams.
Es porque sigues apareciendo en mis sueños.
I was born on-- Just a second.
Nací el… Espera.
Who's calling?
¿Quién será?
What's up? Is a patient waiting?
¿Llegó un paciente?
Dr. Yun!
¡Dra. Yun!
What? What's wrong?
¿Qué pasa?
-Just take it out. -Please leave it there.
- Llévate eso. - No, déjelo ahí.
-Just do as I say! -Gosh!
¡Solo haz lo que te digo!
What is happening?
¿Qué está pasando?
"The contract ended a long time ago.
"El contrato terminó hace mucho tiempo.
I can't let this go on. I won't put up with this anymore!"
¡No aguantaré más esto!".
That's what the chairman said.
Eso es lo que dijo el presidente.
"I'm an old man who lives off the rental income from this building.
"Soy un anciano que vive del alquiler de este edificio.
My safety is being threatened because of that evil tenant."
Mi seguridad está amenazada por esa malvada inquilina".
Those were also his words.
Esas fueron sus palabras.
What are you talking about? I said I'll pay more deposit.
¿De qué hablas? Dije que pagaré más depósito.
Didn't you tell him?
¿No le dijiste?
I did, but he suddenly wants us out of here today no matter what.
Sí, pero solo quiere que nos vayamos.
Just leave it there!
¡Déjelo ahí!
What kind of nonsense is this?
¿Qué tontería es esta?
Just leave that there, please!
¡Deja eso ahí!
By the way, I heard that
Por cierto, escuché por ahí
this was all decided by the chairman's beloved granddaughter,
que esto lo decidió la querida nieta del presidente,
Ms. Shin Ja-ya,
la señorita Shin Ja-ya,
who is the real power behind the throne.
quien es la que realmente tiene el poder.
Ms. Shin Ja-ya.
- La Srta. Shin Ja-ya. - ¿Qué?
What did you say? Shin Ja-ya?
¿Qué dijiste? ¿Shin Ja-ya?
Take your filthy hands off everything.
Saquen sus sucias manos de ahí.
Mr. Ma.
Señor Ma.
Put everything back where it was. Don't move anything.
Devuelvan todo a donde estaba.
Hey, you! Put that down.
¡Oye, tú!
Mr. Ma, it's okay. It's nothing serious.
Señor Ma, está bien. No es nada grave.
Don't get worked up. Just wait outside, please.
No se enoje. Espéreme afuera, por favor.
Don't touch anything.
No toquen nada.
Who says you can kick her out of this building?
¿Quiénes se creen?
I told you not to touch anything!
¡Que no toques nada!
-What is your problem? -I told you not to touch anything!
- ¿Cuál es tu problema? - ¡Que no toquen nada!
-Mr. Ma! -Don't touch anything!
- ¡Señor Ma! - ¡No toquen nada!
-Mr. Ma, stop! -Calm down!
- ¡Pare, Sr. Ma! - ¡Cálmese!
-Mr. Ma! -You bastard!
- ¡Sr. Ma! - ¡Maldito!
Get out!
¡Fuera de aquí!
Be quiet!
¡Cállate!
He's my patient.
Es mi paciente.
He has trouble controlling his emotions.
Le cuesta controlar sus emociones.
I'm his psychiatrist. I'll take responsibility.
Yo asumiré la responsabilidad.
Please let him go and--
Déjelo ir y…
We haven't been able to do anything because he's going bonkers.
No hemos podido controlarlo. Está loco.
How can we let him go?
¿Cómo podemos dejarlo ir?
Let's talk when his guardian gets here.
Esperemos a su guardián.
Excuse me, Officer.
Disculpe, oficial.
I didn't even punch him once.
No lo golpeé ni siquiera una vez.
That guy also participated in the assault,
Él también participó en la pelea,
so they'll both have to come to an agreement.
así que ambos tendrán arreglarse.
His guardian is out of the country at the moment.
Su guardián está fuera del país por el momento.
It'll take some time for someone else to come.
Tomará tiempo que venga alguien más.
Don't shut down my psychiatrist's clinic! How could anyone with a heart do this?
¡No cierres la clínica!
You heartless bastard! You're--
¡Maldito despiadado! ¡Eres…!
Please be quiet!
Por favor, cállate.
Ms. Yun.
Señorita Yun.
Mr. Shin, I'm here!
¡Señor Shin, aquí estoy!
-We're okay now. -Hello.
- Estaremos bien. - Hola.
Don't worry about these two. You should just...
No te preocupes por ellos.
focus on dealing with the aftermath. Thank you.
Tú preocúpate del resto. Gracias.
I'll call you later.
Te llamo luego.
-May I hold your arm? -Pardon?
- ¿Me da su brazo? - ¿Qué?
You look like you're about to collapse.
Se ve exhausta.
I'm all right.
Estoy bien.
Why did Sang-yu do such a useless thing?
¿Por qué Sang-yu hizo algo tan inútil?
It's not useless. I'm so glad he did it.
No fue inútil. Me alegro que lo haya hecho.
Give him a raise.
Dele un aumento.
I laughed a little after I got your call.
Me reí después de su llamada.
I realized you probably don't have that many friends, just like me.
Me di cuenta de que no tiene tantos amigos. Al igual que yo.
Why did you have to be so difficult when I asked you to be my friend?
¿Por qué se negó tanto a ser mi amiga?
What do you say now? Isn't it nice to have a rich friend?
¿Qué dice ahora? ¿No es bueno tener un amigo rico?
Do you want something to drink?
¿Quiere beber algo?
-I just want to go home and rest. -All right, then.
Solo quiero descansar.
Get in. I'll drive you home.
Suba. La llevaré a casa.
It's not too far from here. I'll just walk.
Caminaré. Vivo cerca.
The cool breeze will help me recollect myself.
- La brisa fresca me recompondrá. - Está bien.
Then I'll call you later to make sure you got home safely.
La llamaré para ver que llegue bien.
Thank you so much for today.
Muchas gracias por su ayuda.
Get home safely.
Que llegue bien.
MR. SHIN HU-YE
SR. SHIN HU-YE
Hello?
¿Aló?
Are you home yet?
¿Ya llegó?
No, not yet.
No, aún no.
I knew it.
Lo sabía. Dijo que vivía cerca.
I'm walking slowly.
Estoy caminando lento.
Then I'll have to call you again to make sure you got home safely.
Entonces la llamaré de nuevo para ver que llegue a salvo.
I recently found out that the granddaughter
Hace poco descubrí que la nieta del dueño del edificio
of the building owner is a girl who hated me in school.
me odiaba en la escuela.
I don't even care to know what she's up to.
Ni siquiera me importa saber de su vida.
I wonder why she hates me so much.
Me pregunto por qué me odia tanto.
We have a lot in common.
Tenemos mucho en común.
Pardon?
¿Por qué?
I'm also suffering because of those kinds of people.
También sufro por ese tipo de gente.
What will you do about the clinic?
¿Qué hará con la clínica?
I'll either have to meet the landlord and beg him to change his mind
Tendré que rogarle al dueño que cambie de opinión
or go see his granddaughter
o ir a rogarle a su nieta, supongo.
Do you want me to go with you?
¿La acompaño?
I'm pretty good at threatening people.
Soy bueno amenazando a la gente.
What?
¿Qué?
Or should I just buy that building?
¿O mejor compro el edificio?
I mean, I'm pretty rich myself.
Tengo el dinero suficiente.
I'm being serious.
Hablo en serio.
I told you not to stay out late.
Te dije que no lo salieras tarde.
You never listen to me, do you?
Nunca me escuchas, ¿cierto?
Habaek is back.
- Habaek regresó. - Vine a despedirme.
I want to love you with no regrets.
Quiero amarte.
She is Habaek's woman. I was one step too late.
Es la mujer de Habaek. Llegué tarde.
The war begins now.
Ahora empieza la guerra.
If you can't win her heart,
Si no puedes ganarte su corazón, tómalo a la fuerza.
Why do you keep acting like you don't know how I feel about you?
¿Por qué sigues ignorándome?
If this is a dream, I hope I never wake up.
Si es un sueño, no quiero despertar.
I'll wait. I'm good at waiting.
Esperaré. Soy bueno en eso.
Get away from him! I can't stand this.
¡Aléjate de él! No soporto esto.
-Have you forgotten? -No way.
- ¿Lo olvidaste? - No puede ser.
-I'm capable of... -I thought I was mistaken.
- Soy capaz de… - Creí me equivoqué.
...killing you guys.
…matarlos.